{
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "prompt": "What special prop should always be included for lists of elements?",
            "answers": [
                "id",
                "name",
                "key",
                "prop"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 2
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "prompt": "A React component is a function that returns ______.",
            "answers": [
                "HTML",
                "JSX",
                "props",
                "state"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "prompt": "Which event handler will run when a user is finished filling out a form?",
            "answers": [
                "onSubmit",
                "onClick",
                "onChange",
                "onForm"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 0
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "prompt": "______ is a tool that transpiles JSX into valid JavaScript.",
            "answers": [
                "React",
                "Babel",
                "Webpack",
                "ES6"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "prompt": "What syntax makes it possible to unpack values from arrays, or properties from objects, into distinct variables?",
            "answers": [
                "spread",
                "key-value",
                "coalescing",
                "destructuring"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 3
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "prompt": "Returning different elements from a component depending on the state of your application is known as _____ rendering.",
            "answers": [
                "voodoo",
                "conditional",
                "reactive",
                "controlled"
            ],
            "correctIndex": 1
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "prompt": "A controlled component is a component that derives its input values from ____.",
            "answers": [
                "State",
                "useEffect",
                "Array",
                "Props"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "prompt": "Event listeners cannot be attached directly to our custom React components.",
            "answers": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "prompt": "React will always re-render a component when the setState function is called.",
            "answers": [
                "False",
                "True"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "prompt": "A React function component must start with a capital letter.",
            "answers": [
                "False",
                "True"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "prompt": "We use a/an ______ to pass data into a component.",
            "answers": [
                "Object",
                "useEffect",
                "Array",
                "Props"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "prompt": "When should you use the key prop?",
            "answers": [
                "I don't know",
                "Any time '.map' is used in a component",
                "When rendering an array of components",
                "If two components are siblings"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "prompt": "Natasha is building a Twitter clone, and is trying to fetch some data from the Twitter API when her App component loads. What is the best approach to doing this?",
            "answers": [
                "Making the user click a button and handling the fetch request in the click event handler.",
                "Using the useEffect hook to fetch all the tweets she initially needs.",
                "I don't know.",
                "Making the fetch request directly in the body of the component function. "
            ],
            "correctIndex": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "prompt": "Natasha now wants her users to be able to update their profiles in her Twitter clone. A user should be able to update their profile by filling out and submitting a form. She'll then need to take the data from the form and send it to her backend by making a PATCH request. Should she handle this action with the useEffect hook, or by attaching an event listener?",
            "answers": [
                "I don't know.",
                "useEffect, because she needs the data immediately when the page loads.",
                "Event listener, because she only wants the fetch to fire when the user is done updating their profile."
            ],
            "correctIndex": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "prompt": "When we're using the useEffect hook, React gives us a way to control when the side effect function will run. What is it?",
            "answers": [
                "By passing a second argument to useEffect of a dependencies array.",
                "By calling the useEffect inside an if/else statement.",
                "I don't know",
                "By running a cleanup function in a useEffect callback function."
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 16,
            "prompt": "When and why should we use a cleanup function with useEffect?",
            "answers": [
                "Any time we make a network request with fetch.",
                "If we have a long running function that we want to stop running when our component is no longer the page.",
                "I don't know.",
                "Always, just to be safe. "
            ],
            "correctIndex": "1"
        },
        {
            "id": 17,
            "prompt": "Which hook gives us the ability to programmatically navigate the user to a new page in our application?",
            "answers": [
                "useState",
                "useParams",
                "useHistory",
                "I don't know."
            ],
            "correctIndex": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": 18,
            "prompt": "______ is the process of handling all the routing logic with JavaScript, without making any additional GET requests for some new HTML document.",
            "answers": [
                "Client-Side Routing",
                "Virtual DOM",
                "useEffect",
                "useHistory"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 19,
            "prompt": "Server-side routing happens when the route is handled internally by the JavaScript that is loaded on the page.",
            "answers": [
                "False",
                "True"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 20,
            "prompt": "The useParams hook allows a component to access data based on the dynamic portion of the URL, such as /dogs/:id.",
            "answers": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 21,
            "prompt": "We use ______ to change the browser's URL and show the user a new page in our application without making the user click on a link.",
            "answers": [
                "Dynamic Routing",
                "Client-Side Routing",
                "I don't know",
                "Programmatic Navigation"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "3"
        },
        {
            "id": 22,
            "prompt": "Which hook should we use to access the dynamic pieces of a URL?",
            "answers": [
                "I don't know.",
                "useState",
                "useParams",
                "useHistory"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "2"
        },
        {
            "id": 23,
            "prompt": "Which of the following commands will download all the packages listed in a package.json file?",
            "answers": [
                "npm init",
                "npm install",
                "npm start",
                "npm run"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        },
        {
            "id": 24,
            "prompt": "is a package manager for JavaScript that works with your JavaScript project directories via the command line, allowing you to install packages of preexisting code.",
            "answers": [
                "npm",
                "JSX",
                "BABEL",
                "HTML"
            ],
            "correctIndex": "0"
        }
    ],
    "flashcards": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "prompt": "State",
            "answer": "The state is a built-in React object that is used to contain data or information about the component. A component's state can change over time; whenever it changes, the component re-renders."
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "prompt": "React",
            "answer": "React is a declarative, efficient, and flexible JavaScript library for building user interfaces. It lets you compose complex UIs from small and isolated pieces of code called 'components.'"
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "prompt": "Is setState synchronous or asynchronous?",
            "answer": "setState is asynchronous, though it may act like it's synchronous. When calling setState, React waits for all components have finished calling setState to then re-render components. This boosts performance and reduces unneccessary re-renders."
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "prompt": "JSX",
            "answer": "JSX is a syntax notation for Javascript XML and provides expressiveness of JavaScript along with HTML."
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "prompt": "virtual DOM",
            "answer": "The virtual DOM (VDOM) is a programming concept where a virtual representation of a UI is kept in memory and synced with the 'real' DOM by a library such as ReactDOM. This process is called reconciliation. React uses a diffing algorithm to update only the changes it finds."
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "prompt": "Props",
            "answer": "Props are arguments passed into React components and are passed down similar to HTML attributes. Props are read-only and can be JavaScript expressions, string literals, callback functions, and other components."
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "prompt": "React Router",
            "answer": "This is a JavaScript (user-interface framework) library developed by engineers at Facebook."
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "prompt": "ReactJS",
            "answer": "React Router is a standard library for routing in React and is used mainly for developing single page applications and offers dynamic routing. Some of its components are BrowserRouter, Route, Link, and Switch."
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "prompt": "JSX element",
            "answer": "A basic unit of JSX found in a JavaScript file which is treated as, and has the functionality of, a JavaScript expression. It can also have attributes, just like HTML elements."
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "prompt": "A JSX expression must have",
            "answer": "exactly one outermost element."
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "prompt": "ReactDOM",
            "answer": "This is a JavaScript library that contains several React-specific methods, all of which deal with the DOM in some way or another."
        }
    ]
}